citizensadvice.org.uk 2014-03-01

# Privacy policy and use of cookies

Citizens Advice is committed to safeguarding your privacy, while providing a high quality of service. Citizens Advice will treat your personal information as confidential and your details will not be given or sold to anyone. 

We will use the information collected online to help us understand more about how our site is used by visitors, and to develop and enhance our services to you.

## Cookies

We use cookies* on this website to:

  * track aspects of user visits, including the length of a user's visit, their browser, geographic location and the use of the search facility on this website
  * remember users selected contrast and/or text resizing style preferences for this website
  * record a user's video preferences for our YouTube videos viewed on this website.

### Cookie name, purpose and expiry details

**Cookie name**|  **Purpose**|  **Expires**  
---|---|---  
__utma| Used to determine unique visitors to this site and it is updated with each page view. Additionally, this cookie is provided with a unique ID that Google Analytics uses to ensure both the validity and accessibility of the cookie as an extra security measure.† | 2 years from set/update  
__utmb| Used to establish and continue a user session with this site.† | 30 minutes from set/update  
__utmc| Used to determine whether or not to establish a new session for the user.† | At end of session  
__utmz| Stores the type of referral used by a visitor to reach this site, whether via a direct method, a referring link, a website search, or a campaign such as an ad or an email link. It is used to calculate search engine traffic, ad campaigns and page navigation within this site. The cookie is updated with each page view to this site.† | 6 months from set/update  
citaContrast| Stores user's colour scheme preference.| 1 year  
citaStyleJS| Stores user's text size preference.| 1 year  
eprivacy| Stops the banner message about cookies showing on every page. It is only shown on the first three pages visited, or until it is closed.| 1 year  
NID| Google cookie typically written to the browser upon the loading of Google Plus One social media buttons.| At end of session  
PREF| Google cookie typically written to the browser upon the loading of Google Plus One social media buttons.| At end of session  
SESSION| Allows a user to login.| At end of session  
ANONID| Used to store temporary information for shopping baskets or other forms that need to remember information between pages.| At end of session  
CABinterest| For logged in users this is used to see how different types of users are using our pages.| At end of session  
CABLogon| Remembers a user's login details so they don't need to login each time.| 1 year  
CABTagView| Remembers if a user has choosen to view tags as a list or cloud.| 1 year  
  
*cookie - a bit of information kept on a user's computer.

† For more information: <http://code.google.com/apis/analytics/docs/concepts/gaConceptsCookies.html>

### How you can manage or delete cookies

If you don't want to receive cookies, you can change settings in your web browser so that your browser tells you when cookies are sent to it or you can refuse cookies altogether. You can also delete cookies that have already been set.

If you wish to restrict or block web browser cookies, the Help function within your browser should tell you how. Alternatively, these sites can provide more information on how to do this:

## Your personal information

When you provide Citizens Advice with personal information, for example, when using the email alert or volunteer request forms, we take steps to ensure that your information is treated securely. For full details of how we handle your personal information:

  * Citizens Advice information charter

Citizens Advice makes every effort to ensure the 

security and integrity of emails on our systems. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information after we’ve received it, Citizens Advice cannot ensure or guarantee the security of information when it is being transmitted.

**Note** : This privacy policy only covers this website www.citizensadvice.org.uk and all pages within it; other websites linked from this website are not covered by this policy. Once you have accessed another website via one of our links you will be subject to the security and privacy policy of that site.
